# Devon M. Mason

12238 Bayhill Drive, Carmel, IN 46033, United States ● 317.502.4648 ● devonmmason@gmail.com ● www.devonmeetsworld.com

Entrepreneurial-driven analyst with a passion for building businesses by utilizing a global network. 4+ year track-record of developing strategy through custom data frameworks. Excels in a collaborative team environment with shared goal of challenging the status quo

## Strengths

**Event Planning** 

**Detail Oriented** 

Multitasking

Persistence

**Flexibility** 

Ingenuity

**Critical Thinking** 

## Work Experience

09/2017 - Present

#### Devonmeetsworld.com

Chief Content Creator, Carmel, IN

- Tailored travel itineraries according to survey results resulting in stress-free trips for 20+ international clients
- Doubled site readership by launching "The Expat Files" educating hundreds on cultural and professional aspects of life abroad
- Curated content for travel-related websites and secured inbound links to boost organic ranking by 20%
- Increased brand awareness and secured freelance writing assignments by introducing a panel at the 2018 Women in Travel Summit in Quebec City

08/2016 - 09/2017

#### DICKS's Sporting Goods

Assistant Inventory Planner- New Stores, Coraopolis, PA

- Developed company-wide communication tool to allow seamless communication from field to inventory planners to modify product assortment and contributed \$99M in 2017 Q1 market share capture
- Prepared financial inventory targets for six Houston market store openings by analyzing space planning data and ensuring instocks for key items resulting in multimillion dollar opening weekend sales
- Aggressively tracked competitor openings and reworked product flow using JDA software to ensure consistent product offerings across departments
- Forecasted opening weekend specials and worked cross-functionally with pricing department to verify sales surpassed gross margin standards

08/2015 - 08/2016

#### **DICKS's Sporting Goods**

Merchandising Trainee, Coraopolis, PA

- •Presented actionable recommendations throughout 6-part rotational program for departments in Buying, Allocations & Replenishment, Supply Chain, Product Development, eCommerce, and Store Experience
- Analyzed competitive landscape of particular store and outlined enhancements to combat product assortment gaps which increased quarterly turnover of clearance items
- Capitalized on Back-to-School season by creating survey for regional store managers thus boosting peak week sales by 15%
- Utilized market research to implement trending items report to pinpoint future product development opportunities

### Education

08/2011 - 05/2015

#### **Indiana University Bloomington**

Kelley School of Business, Bloomington, Indiana

Bachelor of Science in Business. Rewarded IU Excellence Scholarship. Graduated with High Distinction and a cumulative GPA of 3.84.

01/2014 - 06/2014

### University of Cape Town

Faculty of Commerce, Cape Town, South Africa

Finance and Humanities Coursework. Curated professionalism workshop for high school students at Christian Organization The Ark.

#### Interests



Landscape Photography



Travel Writing



Hiking



Improv Comedy



Acro Yoga



Sewing